# Kenneth Kaijage

586 Falcon Ridge Rd Woodbury, MN 55125 ■ kennykaijage@gmail.com ② (763)-742-2834 Kenny Kaijage Portfolio

## **SUMMARY**

An experienced professional with a Bachelor's degree in Statistics and a minor in Economics with a passion of understanding data. Analytical, action oriented, and hardworking with a strong ability of utilizing critical thinking and teamwork to solve problems.

## **EDUCATION**

## **University of Minnesota-Twin Cities**

Minneapolis, MN

Bachelor of Arts, Major in Statistics, Minor in Economics

September 2016 – May 2020

- Cumulative GPA: 3.08/4.0; Dean's list Spring 2020.
- Area of Emphasis; Statistical Practice.
- Relevant Coursework: Intro to C++; Theory of Statistics; Regression and Correlated Data; Intermediate Microeconomics; Intermediate Macroeconomics; Introduction to Statistical Computing; Applied Statistics; Public Economics; Statistics Designing Experiments; Communication for Statisticians.

#### **SKILLS**

Teamwork/Leadership	Critical Thinking	R	Microsoft Excel
Project Management	<b>Technical Documentation</b>	Python	SQL/MySQL/PostGreSQL
Analytics and Reporting	Problem Solving	Power BI	<b>Business Process Design</b>
Tableau	Microsoft Azure Fundamentals	Microsoft SQL Server	Azure Data Studio
Github	HTML/Web development	Statistical Analysis	Data Analysis/Analytics

# **WORK Experience**

Accenture

Minneapolis, MN

Consulting Development Analyst Functional and Industry Analytics Senior Analyst August 2021 – November 2022 November 2022 – Present

# **Project Experiences**

Data Quality Analyst

July 2022 - Present

- Creating Microsoft automation flows to automatically send emails to project managers to improve data quality and audits for reports
- Constructing SQL queries to create and update reports for audits which are used by the Microsoft automation flows and following up with client project managers for missing variables and fields in the reports.
- Assisting the team with creating SQL queries, data validations and utilizing Excel tools such as Pivot Tables to create new reports for data analysis and reporting and generate reports for stakeholders.
- Assisted in creating a Tableau dashboard to assist with data cleaning efforts in order to help the company save costs and allow them to use their monthly budget for allocation and optimization.
- Creating Excel reports using SQL in order to run monthly audits with the purpose of conducting data cleaning
  efforts for 100+ projects before the month's fiscal date and ensure the client maximized capitalization of over \$50
  million dollars in costs. This involved taking care of missing names and determining how the project was financed
  and using Excel X-Lookups to further check for additional fields in other data sources not found in SQL server
  databases.
- Creating SQL queries using the client's data that will then be fed into Power-BI and Tableau Dashboards to provide the client with the desired metrics and data coming from a variety of different project management tools.

Business Analyst January 2022 – June 2022

- Conducted data analysis on the Visit types using Excel to analyze and determine the highest occurrences of a
  patient's reasons of visit per center during the 2019 to 2022 period. Used the analysis to create visuals that
  illustrated the centers with a high visit volume that were to be prioritized for the CRM scheduling framework.
- Conducted blocks data analysis using Excel to analyze the highest number of block usage when the patient gets
  scheduled for a visit. Used the data analysis to create visuals and a report that illustrated the highest number of
  block usage and recommended to the team to remove blocks that were least used from 2021 and onwards.
- Supported the clinical scripting workflow through the creation of clinical scripts and data analysis on keyword mapping. Conducted the keyword mapping data analysis using Excel to match symptoms with similar or different naming to ensure that they are accounted in the CRM scheduling framework.

## Data Analyst

September 2021 – December 2021

- Assisted in creating an underlying data process to streamline and automate data from various sources to support
  reporting and dashboards and constructed data tables and views within the ETL development environment in the
  Microsoft SQL server database for SSI package development and the data migration process.
- Created design documents, data tables and structures in the ETL development process and test scripts and assisted in the data cleaning and data organization from the ETL development stage to the data migration stage.
- Loaded the data into the server for clean-up, end-to-end testing and migration to support dashboard building, reporting, and wireframe completion.

US Bank Saint Paul, MN

Global Securities Specialist

June 2020 - August 2021

- Worked with clients and administrators in creating and managing global accounts for trade.
- Analyzed and rectified invalid trade instructions in the market via SWIFT and inbound SWIFTS (electronically sent trades).
- Made recommendations with other global teams to best meet the client and their business needs.
- Worked on internal projects for the specific team and at the global custody level.
- Assisted in the MUFG conversion for advanced markets such as South Korea and Brazil.